<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>The Trading Developer Blog</title>
        <link>https://simoneb.github.io/trading-blog/</link>
        <description>The Trading Developer Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 19:20:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The systematic trading journey of a professional software developer]]></title>
            <link>https://simoneb.github.io/trading-blog/the-systematic-trading-journey-of-a-professional-software-developer</link>
            <guid>https://simoneb.github.io/trading-blog/the-systematic-trading-journey-of-a-professional-software-developer</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 19:20:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As in the most classic tradition of software development]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As in the most <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%22Hello,_World!%22_program" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">classic tradition</a> of software development</p><div class="language-bash codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#393A34;--prism-background-color:#f6f8fa"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-bash codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#393A34"><span class="token plain">$ Hello world</span><span class="token operator" style="color:#393A34">!</span><span class="token plain"> </span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>I've been in software development for many years and I recently started my journey into the world of systematic trading.</p><p>Although I've been trading equities for a few years now, I never seriously got into it. I mainly copied others' investment ideas, or followed hearsay and other not very scientific ways to make investment decisions. </p><p>Then, in late September 2022 I eventually decided that it was about time I took a step in what is hopefully a better way of doing it. Being a software developer, the approach that felt most natural to me was that of systematic trading.</p><p>Back then I didn't have a clear idea of what that meant. I assumed it involved writing some sort of software program that would do the trading more or less autonomously.</p><h1>Choosing a training course</h1><p>I never followed any training courses on trading or investment, so I ended up relying on my gut feeling to choose one. </p><p>There are many options out there and I went with <a href="https://ungeracademy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unger Academy</a>. The main reason is that in their ads and the few <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@UngerAcademy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a> videos I had watched they seemed to know what they were talking about. Note that I am not promoting nor am I affiliated to them in any way.</p><h1>What is systematic trading</h1><p>The first time I heard about systematic trading I was both attracted and scared by the idea of a program running day and night, trading on my behalf. </p><p>The thought of writing a program was exciting - after all that's what I do for a living - while that of operating complex infrastructure was quite daunting.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://github.com/simoneb/trading-blog/assets/20181/de2499e9-4022-491f-bde6-4395fb0c1017" alt="image" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Systematic trading basically boils down to:</p><ol><li>Coming up with a trading idea to apply on a certain asset</li><li>Writing a program to execute it</li><li>Backtesting it against historical data to validate it</li><li>Using specialized software to run and automate it</li></ol><p>Obviously, this is all easier said than done, and there are great amounts of knowledge that go into each step, and many decisions to be made along the way.</p><h1>What to expect</h1><p>In this blog I am going to document and share my journey, along with takeaways, struggles and useful things I create along the way.</p><p>When you start learning something new it's particularly effective to capture it. The beginning is when the most "aha!" moments will happen, and I have collected quite a few already, which are worth sharing.</p><p>If there's anything that you're specifically interested into, post it in the comments below.</p><p><strong>Stay tuned!</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>